if you're a doctor here are three things
you should check before buying a
professional Indemnity insurance
number one make sure the policy covers
out of court settlements and lawyer fees
not all court cases go till the Judgment
so the out of court settlement and loyal
fees in itself can be large amounts
number two be aware of how the amount
insured is split now you may have a
policy of 50 lakhs but that can be split
in different ways a policy may give a
total maximum some payout of 50 lakhs
for a single case in a single year or it
may be split as two cases permitted with
a maximum payout of 25 lakhs per case or
some policies may just mention a total
payout of 50 lakhs irrespective of the
number of cases but you should be aware
of what that policy is and choose
accordingly
number three if you're a member of a
medical association or any association
of your specialty you should check with
them if they offer any professional
Indemnity insurances it usually is a
policy from a bank but you tend to get a
better deal if you're going through an
association